PHILLIP PATTERSON

■ phillip.s.patterson1@gmail.com • philpatterson.io in /in/philpatt/ • philpatt

SUMMARY

My years of experience in analytical science has strengthened my attention to detail, problem solving and reinforced the necessary soft-skills needed for a collaborative environment. I have a desire to grow and continuously learn to strengthen my passion of

PROJECTS

- HTML 5, CSS 3, Diango, Python 3, PostgreSOL,
- Using the Django built-in administration site to manage custom relational databases that help manage Maine Mussels Youth Lacrosse Organization and to create custom front-end displays

- HTML 5, CSS 3, Javascript, jQuery, PostgreSQL, RESTful API/AJAX, Node, and Express This app allows you to access the National Park Service's API and save up to date info

- HTML 5, CSS 3, Javascript, React, MongoDb/Mongoose, Node and Express
- Flashcard was a collaborative effort to create a React JS application that allows a user to create electronic flashcards that they can quiz themselves with to improve their learning experience

Connect 4

- HTML 5, CSS 3, Javascript, jQuery

 Based off the common childhood game, Connect 4, two players play against each other, alternating turns, to get 4 game pieces in a row (horizontal, vertical, or horizontal)

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Full-Stack Web Developer Nov 2017 - Mar 2018

- Spent 700+ hours in a collaborative project-based web development course focused on full stack application with short and rigorous deadlines
- Highly focused on the implementation of the MERN stack with exposure to ReactUS, Python, and Django

 Highly efficient in using Git workflow version control and white-boarding design techniques to complete deliverables in short 1 week sprints

 Other Technologies: Web Scraping(Cheerio)

Aug 2017 - Nov 2017 Aspenti Health, Data Review and Confirmation Scientist, Burlington, Vermont

- Established new employee work schedule that increased specimen turn-around time by 50%. Collected and processed data acquired from analytical instrumentation. Troubleshoot instrumentation and investigate oberrant test results.

 Performed routine maintenance and troubleshooting of equipment.

Data Review and Confirmation Scientist, Burlington, Vermont

Aug 2017 - Nov 2017

- Established new employee work schedule that increased specimen turn-around time by 50% Collected and processed data acquired from analytical instrumentation
- Troubleshoot instrumentation and investigate aberrant test results
- Performed routine maintenance and troubleshooting of equipment

Mylan Technologies, Quality Control Analytical Chemist, St. Albans, Vermont

Aug 2014 - Aug 2016

- Performed analytical testing on all of Mylan Technology pharmaceutical transdermal products (12 different patches in varied doses).
 Short term(I hour) and long term(I month) analysis of transdermal patches, which increased delivery of product quality.
 Interpreted test results and ensured that they met specifications and performed analytical investigations to address oberrant test results . Worked along-side chemists, scientists, and managers in a collaborative environment.

Quality Control Analytical Chemist, St. Albans, Vermont

Aug 2014 - Aug 2016

- Performed analytical testing on all of Mylan Technology pharmaceutical transdermal products (12 different patches in varied doses) Short term(1 hour) and long term(1 month) analysis of transdermal patches, which increased delivery of product auglity
- Interpreted test results and ensured that they met specifications and performed analytical investigations to address aberrant test results.

 Worked along-side chemists, scientists, and managers in a collaborative environment

University of Vermont Medical Center, Phlehotomist, Burlington, Vermont

Nov 2013 - Aug 2014

- Obtained multiple blood specimens from up to 30 patients a day iatric to obtain samples in a safe and efficient manner - Performed phlebotomy in multiple healthcare settings (psychiatric ward, pre and post-operation, inpatient, and outpatient)

EDUCATION

General Assembly

12 week immersive Web Development Program

Castleton University

SKILLS

FRONT-END: HTML, CSS, Javascript, ¡Query, React, Django, AJAX, Express Js BACK-END: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Python 3, Node JS TECHNICAL: Git / GitHub, Wire Framing, Web-Scraping (Cheerio)

ACTIVITIES

Nominated Captain in 2013

Castleton Men's Lacrosse Aug 2009 - May 2013

Castleton Mentoring Program, Mentor May 2010 - May 2010

Rochester Area Sports Trail Alliance, Trail Maintenance Volunteer

Aug 2016 - Nov 2016